{
    "title": "CYBR-2500-Midterm Short Answer",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Name the three basic tasks all computers perform?",
            "correct_answer": "input, processing, output",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the physical address assigned to NICs called?",
            "correct_answer": "MAC address",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the more well-known term for chunks of data sent across the network?",
            "correct_answer": "packets",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name given to software that provides the interface between the OS and computer hardware?",
            "correct_answer": "device driver",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the network service that provides name resolution services that allow users to access both local and Internet servers by name rather than address?",
            "correct_answer": "DNS server",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which component provides a number of critical services, including a user interface, memory management, a file system, multitasking, and the interface to hardware devices?",
            "correct_answer": "operating system",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Is Random Access Memory (RAM) short-term or long-term storage?",
            "correct_answer": "short-term",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What term is used to describe a networked collection of LANs tied together by devices such as routers?",
            "correct_answer": "internetwork",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "The client/server networking model may also be known as?",
            "correct_answer": "server-based",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between a client and a server, in networking terms?",
            "correct_answer": "A client requests information or a service, while the server is what responds to the client's request.",
            "type": "short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does a repeater do?",
            "correct_answer": "Expands the coverage area of a network by amplifying the signal to devices in the vicinity.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a multiport repeater often referred to as?",
            "correct_answer": "a hub",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main difference between a wireless access point and a hub?",
            "correct_answer": "An access point simply provides a secondary location of the network for devices to connect from, increasing the capacity of the network. A hub sets up a local network to manage the devices on the network. Wireless access points need to have an extra step that hubs don't have. Before a computer can submit data, it needs to send a request to send message (RTS). Wireless access points are wireless, and hubs are wired.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the address that is part of a NIC?",
            "correct_answer": "Media Access Control (MAC)",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the amount of data that can be transferred on a network during a specific interval called? ",
            "correct_answer": "bandwidth",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long are MAC addresses?",
            "correct_answer": "12 hexadecimal characters",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "To connect to a wireless network, you need to have the ____",
            "correct_answer": "SSID",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is another name for a port on routers?",
            "correct_answer": "interface",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What tells a router where to send a packet with a destination network that canâ€™t be found in the routing table?",
            "correct_answer": "default route",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "The scope of devices to which broadcast frames are forwarded is known as?",
            "correct_answer": "broadcast domain",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between physical topology and logical topology?",
            "correct_answer": "Physical topology is how devices are connected. Logical topology is how the user thinks of them being connected.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many links would you need in a full mesh configuration if you had 4 nodes?",
            "correct_answer": "6 wires",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the most widely used physical topology in networks today?",
            "correct_answer": "extended star",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________________ is the method a network interface uses to access the medium and send data frames and the structure of these frames.",
            "correct_answer": "network technology",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "When using UTP cabling, what is the maximum cable segment allowed from the computer to a hub or switch?",
            "correct_answer": "100 meters",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the standard that describes 10 Gigabit running over four pairs of CAT6A cabling?",
            "correct_answer": "10GBaseT",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the media access method used by Ethernet?",
            "correct_answer": "CSMA/CD",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the networking standard for wireless networking (also known as Wireless Fidelity or Wi-Fi).",
            "correct_answer": "802.11",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which media access method is used by FDDI?",
            "correct_answer": "token-passing",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________________ is a broadband technology used to deliver Internet access to homes and businesses over standard cable television (CATV) coaxial cable.",
            "correct_answer": "cable modem networking",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the process called that determines how bits are represented on the medium?",
            "correct_answer": "encoding",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the two types of interference often encountered when using copper media?",
            "correct_answer": "Electromagnetic Interference (EMI) and Radio Frequency Interference (RFI)",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a short cable for connecting a computer to an RJ-45 jack or connecting a patch-panel port to a switch or hub?",
            "correct_answer": "patch cable",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which category of UTP is the recommended cabling standard for 1 Gbps over copper media?",
            "correct_answer": "CAT6",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Horizontal wiring from the wall jack to the patch panel should be no longer than?",
            "correct_answer": "90 meters",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the device that is used to translate between wired and wireless networks?",
            "correct_answer": "Transceiver/access point",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Name the two main types of fiber-optic cable.",
            "correct_answer": "Single-mode fiber (SMF) and Multimode fiber (MMF)",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which fiber-optic media type uses light-emitting diodes (LEDs) instead of lasers?",
            "correct_answer": "Multimode Fiber (MMF)",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What can connect networks up to three miles?",
            "correct_answer": "Wireless bridges",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of system can send and receive data from geosynchronous satellites that maintain fixed positions in the sky?",
            "correct_answer": "Satellite Microwave systems",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a set of protocols works together cooperatively it is known as a?",
            "correct_answer": "protocol stack",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "At what layer of the TCP/IP suite are IP addresses defined and verified?",
            "correct_answer": "internetwork",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "TCP and UDP use __________________ to specify the source and destination application-layer protocols.",
            "correct_answer": "port numbers",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Transport-layer protocol does DHCP use?",
            "correct_answer": "UDP (User Datagram Protocol)",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What port is associated with the DNS service?",
            "correct_answer": "53",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of protocol is used when no lasting connection is made from source to destination?",
            "correct_answer": "connectionless",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the five IP address class ranges are available for host assignment?",
            "correct_answer": "There are three - class A, class B, and class C.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What allows an organization to use private IP addresses while connected to the Internet.",
            "correct_answer": "NAT (Network Address Translation)",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the process of dividing a single network address into two or more subnetwork addresses, each with fewer available host IDs than the original network address?",
            "correct_answer": "subnetting",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many bits is an IPv6 address rather than the 32 bits in an IPv4 address.",
            "correct_answer": "128 bits",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "The IP address 127.0.0.1 is a reserved address because it used for troubleshooting and is known as what?",
            "correct_answer": "a loopack address",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "A range of addresses is reserved for private addressing in each class. What are those ranges and classes?",
            "correct_answer": "The ranges include Class A 10.0.0.0 and 90.0.0.0, Class B 172.16.0.0 to 172.31.0.0, and Class C 192.168.0.0.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the process of dividing a single network address into two or more subnetwork addresses, each with fewer available host IDs than the original network address?",
            "correct_answer": "subnetting",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between NAT and PAT?",
            "correct_answer": "Both turn private IP addresses into public IP addresses. NAT does this by turning local addresses to global addresses, while PAT does this by translating unregistered IP addresses to registered public IP addresses.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many bits are in an IPv6 address?",
            "correct_answer": "128",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "List and describe three improvements that IPv6 has over IPv4.",
            "correct_answer": "IPv6 is more secure. IPv6 processes packets more efficiently. IPv6 has 128 bit IP addresses, which means there are more IP addresses overall when dealing with IPv6 as opposed to IPv4's 32 bit IP addresses.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "How does a computer know when to send packets to the default gateway?",
            "correct_answer": "Computers determine the network ID by doing a logical AND operation between its IP address and subnet mask.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which command displays the route packets take between two computers?",
            "correct_answer": "traceroute command",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "If all hosts on the same network have different network ID, can they talk?",
            "correct_answer": "No",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why has the OSI Reference Model become such a key part of networking?",
            "correct_answer": "Because it is a common model for students to learn with.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is meant by peer communication between layers?",
            "correct_answer": "Two computers can communicate across a network.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which layer permits two computers to hold ongoing communications across a network, so applications on either end of the session can exchange data for as long as the session lasts?",
            "correct_answer": "session layer",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What PDU is in use at the Transport layer of the OSI model?",
            "correct_answer": "segment based",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the IEEE 802 standards, each number after the dot represents a different _______________________.",
            "correct_answer": "technology",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "The segmenting of the data is important because every network technology has a maximum frame size called the ____________________________________.",
            "correct_answer": "Maximum Transmission Unit",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why did the IEEE feel the need to develop LAN standards?",
            "correct_answer": "To make sure network interfaces would be compatible with each other.",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the names of the two sublayers of the data link layer?",
            "correct_answer": "LLC, MAC",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which sublayer defines the use of logical interface points, called Service Access Points (SAPs)?",
            "correct_answer": "LLC",
            "type":"short_answer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which 802 standard describes Token Ring?",
            "correct_answer": "IEEE 802.5",
            "type":"short_answer"
        }
    ]
}
